Aljon Preza

San Francisco, California · alionpreza@gmail.com · (808) 931-0419 · in/alionpreza · alionpreza.com

Professional Summary

Highly skilled and innovative web and graphic designer with over six years of experience, specializing in creating market-leading brands and websites. Achieved exceptional results, including a 200% increase in unique web visitors and a 50% growth in sales revenue in 2022.

Technical Skills

Design: Figma, Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Lightroom), UX/UI, Brand Design, Video, Print Digital Marketing: Meta (Facebook) Business, Email Marketing (MailChimp), Google Analytics, Social Media, SEO Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress, React, Bootstrap, SASS · Back-end: PHP, Python

Professional Experience

OrthoMasterClass

May 2022 - Present

Web Project Manager

Honolulu, HI

- Successfully built and launched 10+ brands and websites, resulting in \$500k in sales revenue.
- Executed and measured landing pages, Google Analytics, and Facebook Ads, increasing lead generation by 30%.
- Launched marketing strategies, including SEO, social media, and email campaigns, growing web traffic by 150%.
- Directed cross-functional teams and key stakeholders, such as Invisalign, to achieve bottom-line objectives.

OrthoMasterClass

March 2017 - May 2022

Web and Graphic Designer

Honolulu, HI

- Drove the UX/UI strategy by conducting user surveys, Figma prototypes, presentations, and framework testing.
- Produced over 300 pieces of marketing collateral, including flyers, brochures, e-books, and slide decks.
- Led social media efforts on Facebook, Instagram, Google, and Yelp, resulting in a 20% increase in acquired users.
- Automated page templates and reduced production time by 70% by customizing WordPress CMS.

RevaComm

November 2016 - January 2017

Web Developer Intern

Honolulu, HI

- Developed and maintained 5+ web applications for top stakeholders in Hawai'i using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Optimized web load times by 50% by effectively reformatting web pages, digital assets, and images.
- Automated the extraction of 100+ Excel files to JSON for a large automotive dealership group using Python.
- Implemented Git version control to streamline software documentation with best practices and coding standards.

Involvement

RadGrad

January 2016 - March 2017

UX/UI Designer

Honolulu, HI

- Designed and developed a degree-planning React web application for 2,000 students.
- Created UX/UI wireframes and prototypes using Adobe Photoshop to optimize usability and responsive design.
- Developed 100+ design elements, templates, and visual brand content using Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator.
- Established and maintained brand identity through visual libraries, typography, layout, and style guidelines.

Education

University of Hawai'i at Mānoa